

# **AKASH DEY**

7439695644 / 9051081391

akash1993dey@gmail.com

Nolkata - India

# **SKILLS**

- Project management
- Complex problem solver
- Code debugger & fixer
- Complex logic implement

### **TECHNOLOGIES**

- Core Java & Java8
- SpringBoot
- Microservice REST
- AWS Cloud
- Chalice & Python
- Thingworx
- HTML & CSS

# **CERTIFICATION**

- SpringBoot Udemy
- AWS Cloud Pluralsight

# **LINKS**

www.linkedin.com/in/akash -dey-329057124

www.github.com/Akash727 80/

# **LANGUAGE**

- English
- Hindi
- Bengali

#### **SUMMARY**

As a senior software developer, I'm the bridge between vision and reality in the digital world. With a mastery of coding languages and knack for problem-solving, I transform complex ideas into elegant, functional software. Being a software developer more than 4 years, I am sincerely aware of the importance of delivering the product within time with proper requirement.

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Senior Software Developer

LTIMindtree

March 2022 - Present

- ♥ Kolkata India
  - Develop IOT based web application using AWS Cloud, Chalice & Python
  - Expert designer in Thingworx
  - Business logic implement and bug fixing.

#### Software Developer

■ Silvertouch Technologies PVT

July 2019 - February 2022

♥ Kolkata - India

- Design and develop web application using SpringBoot for submitting import and export application of container handling agent
- An EIR(Equipment interchange) app developed using SpringBoot for Container movement with help of Geo-location
- Build a mobile based app for Berth & Rake booking using SpringBoot and Oracle database for Vessel berth allotment.

# Software Developer

NRI Fintech

January 2019 - June 2019

♥ Kolkata - India

• Build a full phase web automation using Katalon framework

# **EDUCATION**

# Master of Technology in Computer Science & Engineering

Calcutta University 2017 - 2019

CGP - 8.4/10

Kolkata - India

# **Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science & Engineering**

West Bengal University of Technology

2013 - 2017

CGP - 8.7/10

Kolkata – India